Contact

alisarkeshik@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alisarkeshik (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

JavaScript

jQuery

HTML

Publications

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/ pubmed?term=sarkeshik (Search for Sarkeshik)

Ali Sarkeshik

Full Stack Developer at UC San Diego Extension San Diego, California

Summary

Solutions-driven Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer who uses ingenuity and creativity to build fluid and functional web applications. My previous experience includes method development in Chemistry and Instrumentation (hardware and software troubleshooting) in a resale and OEM environment.

Experience

UC San Diego Extension Full Stack Developer February 2019 - Present Greater San Diego Area

For a list of my coding projects please visit: https://alisarkeshik.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/portfolio.html

Learning front-end and back-end technologies through a dynamic curriculum:

Database Theory, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, MongoDB, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Bookshelf.js, AJAX, Firebase Command Line, and Git

PerkinElmer, Inc.
Customer Support Engineer
June 2018 - December 2018 (7 months)
Greater San Diego Area

- Provided on-site personalized support services for PerkinElmer instruments
- Provided troubleshooting expertise and repair skills needed to help identify and resolve issues related to hardware, software or applications support.
- Performed PMs, installs, and repairs on various Perkin Elmer instruments (Janus, LabChip, SciClone, Zephyr, and Euroimmune products).

Roche Diagnostics
Planned Activities Specialist/Field Service Engineer
January 2018 - May 2018 (5 months)

Page 1 of 3

Greater San Diego Area (Contract position via Tailored Management)

- Performed on-site preventative maintenance, installation, and technical updates (TSB's) on company products (Cobas 6000 and 8000 analyzers).
- Diagnosed mechanical, hardware, software and system failures
- Trained in: CD Foundations of Hardware, IT Products, c6000/8000 Service
 Operator Training, and Cobas 6000 Install/Core Service

BioSurplus, Inc.
Service Engineer
January 2017 - July 2017 (7 months)
Greater San Diego Area

- Determined the re-sale viability of company acquisitions.
- Diagnosed, repaired, and serviced a wide range of laboratory equipment.
- Systems included but were not limited to: Flow Cytometry, Centrifuges,
 Refrigeration Systems, Automated Liquid Handlers, and HPLC.

Versum Materials (Formerly known as Air Products and Chemicals, Inc.)

Analytical Chemist

November 2013 - January 2017 (3 years 3 months)

Carlsbad, CA (Contract Position via The Fountain Group: Nov 2013 – May 2015)

- Worked closely with a team of researchers to support method development for new products.
- Performed hands on installation (hardware/software), calibrations, troubleshooting, and maintenance on GC instruments (Agilent 5973/6850/6890/Thermo Trace 1310).
- GC-TCD/GC-FID, GC-MS, DIP-MS analysis of organo silanes and GC-PHID analysis of Octane
- Successfully assisted in transitioning R&D products to commercial status (ISO: 9001:2008, 17025, 10012)

BP (British Petroleum)
Research Associate
March 2013 - October 2013 (8 months)
Greater San Diego Area (Contract Position via Collabera)

- SEC-HPLC Analysis of: Organic Acids, Sugars, Oligomers, Solids, and Furans in Fermentation and Yeast engineering Samples
- · IC Analysis of Organic Acids

 Headspace GC Analysis and Method Development of Ethanol, Isobutanol, Isobutyl Acetate, and Ethyl Acetate in Fermentation Samples

Ionis Pharmaceuticals (Formerly ISIS Pharmaceuticals)
Research Associate/Scientist - Oligo Synthesis
October 2012 - November 2012 (2 months)

Carlsbad, CA (Contract position via Aerotek)

- Production of synthetic oligonucleotides (using Mermade 192 synthesizer) in a GLP environment
- Analytical techniques used: C5 and C8 SAX purification (GE AKTA Explorer) and C7 Desalt (GE AKTA Avant)
- Utilized Agilent 6130 Quadrople LC-MS to verify fraction purity

The Scripps Research Institute
Research Technician
July 2006 - July 2011 (5 years 1 month)
La Jolla. CA

- Performed hands installation (hardware/software), calibration, troubleshooting, and preventative maintenance on LC/LC-MS (LTQ and LTQ Orbitrap) and HPLC instruments (Agilent 1100)
- Protein characterization and data analysis by Mass Spectrometry (MS) of over 1000 protein complexes
- Technical editing and writing experience: successful construction and implementation of new YRC SOPs, co-authoring scientific publications, creation and maintenance of YRC protocol and instrumentation webpage
- Database maintenance, creation, and modification for YRC Public Data Repository
- Successfully improved YRC data processing system (Data submission, database parsing, etc)

Education

University of California San Diego Certificate, Full Stack Web Development (In Progress) · (2019 - 2019)

University of California, Riverside Chemistry, Bachelor of Science